In past videos we have learned how the CPU works, how to read assembler and how to reverse
在过去的视频中，我们学习了CPU的工作原理、如何读取汇编程序以及如何反转
engineer the functionality of a simple program.
设计简单程序的功能。
In the upcoming videos I want to go a little bit deeper and explore how we can exploit
在接下来的视频中，我想更深入地探讨我们如何利用
a program when we have the ability to corrupt memory.
当我们有能力破坏内存时的程序。
This first video will be more about how to setup and get everything running.
第一个视频将详细介绍如何设置和运行所有内容。
So we can focus on the technical part in the next videos.
所以我们可以在下一个视频中关注技术部分。
The title of this video is inspired by the famous phrack article “Smashing The Stack
这个视频的标题是受著名的短语文章“粉碎堆栈”的启发
” from 1996.
从1996年开始。
You can imagine that a lot of stuff has changed since then.
你可以想象从那时起很多事情都发生了变化。
Though, we first have to learn about the basics, before we can have a look at modern techniques.
尽管如此，我们首先要学习基础知识，然后才能了解现代技术。
We will kind of follow the timeline of exploitation technique discovery and attempted mitigations.
我们将遵循开发技术发现和尝试缓解的时间表。
Like DEP or ASLR, just to name two.
比如DEP或ASLR，就举两个例子。
As basis for the next couple of videos, I will use challenges included in the Linux
作为接下来几段视频的基础，我将使用Linux中包含的挑战
images provided by exploit-exercises.com.
由exploit-exercises.com提供的图像。
This allows you to set up this system as well, which I highly recommend.
这也允许你设置这个系统，我强烈推荐。
With protostar you will start with simple memory corruption and modification, function
使用ProtoStar，您将从简单的内存损坏和修改开始，函数
redirection, and finally executing custom shellcode.
重定向，最后执行自定义shellcode。
In order to make this as easy as possible to introduce, ASLR and Non-Executable memory
为了尽可能容易地引入ASLR和非可执行内存
has been disabled.
已被禁用。
So first download the protostar .iso and boot from it in the VMWare Player.
所以首先下载protostar.iso并在vmware播放器中从中启动。
As you can see it doesn’t start with a nice graphical user-interface like our Ubuntu system
正如你所看到的，它并不像我们的Ubuntu系统那样从一个良好的图形用户界面开始。
does.
做。
But don’t panic, you learned how to use the command-line from the very first episode.
但不要惊慌，你从第一集就学会了如何使用命令行。
Now, I will use this moment to introduce you to `ssh`, which stands for secure shell and
现在，我将利用这个时刻向您介绍“ssh”，它代表安全shell和
is a program that allows us to connect to a system over a network, that has an ssh server
是一个允许我们通过网络连接到系统的程序，它有一个ssh服务器
running.
跑步。
This would be the kind of access you get when you have to administrate servers that run
当您必须管理运行的服务器时，这将是您获得的访问权限。
for example a website.
例如网站。
That’s the reason why I introduced you to the command line in the very first episode,
这就是我在第一集就把你介绍给指挥部的原因，
because you really really have to know how to use it.
因为你真的需要知道如何使用它。
You can also tell that I run windows as a host OS.
您还可以告诉我，我以主机操作系统的身份运行Windows。
I think I haven’t mentioned it before, but the main reason here is, that I imagine the
我想我以前没提过，但主要原因是，我认为
majority of people start out on Windows, which means it’s the best way to reach more people.
大多数人从窗户开始，这意味着这是接触更多人的最佳方式。
We don’t want to be excluding like so many other parts of our societies.
我们不想像我们社会的许多其他部分一样被排除在外。
At least for me, hacking conveys a spirit to be open and share knowledge.
至少对我来说，黑客行为传达了一种开放和分享知识的精神。
So that’s why I have to download PuTTY for Windows now, which is a windows client for
所以我现在必须下载Putty for Windows，它是Windows客户端
ssh.
嘘。
To use it to connect to this machine we have to find the IP address of it.
要使用它连接到这台机器，我们必须找到它的IP地址。
The username and password for the protostar image is just “user”.
ProtoStar映像的用户名和密码只是“用户”。
So use that to login.
所以用它来登录。
And then execute the command `ip addr`, to find the assigned IP and then copy it into
然后执行命令“ip addr”，找到分配的IP，然后将其复制到
putty, save this session and press Open.
油灰，保存此会话并按“打开”。
You have to login again, but this is much better now.
你必须重新登录，但现在好多了。
We can copy data back and forth and we can have multiple connections.
我们可以来回复制数据，也可以有多个连接。
The equivalent for Mac and Linux is just simply `ssh`, the username “user” at the ip address.
对于mac和linux的等价物只是简单的“ssh”，即IP地址的用户名“user”。
Ok.
好啊。
At the moment our shell is /bin/sh.
目前我们的外壳是/bin/sh。
And as you can see, tab-completion doesn’t work.
如你所见，标签完成不起作用。
But we can execute `/bin/bash` instead, which makes the command-line a bit nicer.
但是我们可以改为执行`/bin/bash'，这使得命令行更好一些。
So what do we have here.
我们这里有什么。
With uname -a we can get some system information and we can see that we have a 32bit linux
有了uname-a，我们可以获得一些系统信息，并且可以看到我们有一个32位的Linux
with a 2.6.32 kernel.
内核为2.6.32。
So how does this work now.
现在这是怎么工作的呢？
On the website it says: The levels to be exploited can be found in the /opt/protostar/bin directory.
网站上说：可以在/opt/protostar/bin目录中找到要利用的级别。
Let’s have a look.
让我们看看。
`Ls` to list all files in this directory.
` ls`列出此目录中的所有文件。
Immediately you will notice this weird red background color for the filenames.
你会立刻注意到文件名的这个奇怪的红色背景色。
Let’s have a closer look.
让我们仔细看看。
With `files` we can check the filetype and it tells us that it is a setuid ELF 32bit
使用“files”，我们可以检查文件类型，它告诉我们它是setuid elf 32位
executable.
可执行的。
From earlier videos you may remember that we have never encountered `setuid` before.
从之前的视频中，您可能记得我们从未遇到过'setuid'。
As always, if we want to know something in linux, we can look in the linux manual.
和往常一样，如果我们想在Linux中了解一些东西，我们可以查看Linux手册。
Though, the man page for setuid is actually about the setuid function provided by libc.
不过，setuid的手册页实际上是关于libc提供的setuid函数的。
But that doesn’t bother us, because it might be related.
但这并不困扰我们，因为它可能是相关的。
So let’s see what it says here about this function.
让我们看看它在这里对这个函数说了些什么。
setuid stands for set user identity.
setuid代表set user identity。
And… setuid sets the effective user ID of the calling process.
并且…setuid设置调用进程的有效用户ID。
mhh… with cat /etc/passwd we can see all users on this system.
mhh…通过cat/etc/passwd，我们可以看到这个系统上的所有用户。
Remember our user is called user so we have the id 1001.
记住，我们的用户叫做用户，所以我们有标识1001。
And the root user has id 0.
根用户的ID为0。
So does that mean, that we can simply write a C program as our unprivileged user and execute
这是否意味着，我们可以简单地以非特权用户的身份编写C程序并执行
setuid with id 0, to become root?
将ID为0的setuid变为根？
Obviously not.
显然不是。
That would be horrible.
那太可怕了。
Further down it tells us about possible errors like EPERM which says that the user is not
再往下讲，它告诉我们可能的错误，比如说，eperm说用户不是
privileged and the uid does not match the real uid of the calling process.
特权和uid与调用进程的实际uid不匹配。
Ok… then… what can it be used for?
好的……那么……它能用来做什么？
An example usage is, that a root process might want to drop privileges to an unprivileged
一个示例用法是，根进程可能希望将特权删除到非特权
user, that in case the process gets exploited, the attacker does not gain root privileges.
用户，即在进程被利用的情况下，攻击者不会获得根权限。
So if you have a process that has to start as root but then doesn’t need it anymore,
所以，如果你有一个必须从根开始的过程，但不再需要它，
it’s good to drop them.
把它们放下是好事。
Anyway.
不管怎样。
What does this have to do with our setuid binary?
这与我们的setuid二进制有什么关系？
Let’s open a second ssh session to look at all running processes.
让我们打开第二个ssh会话来查看所有正在运行的进程。
Now open a process that keeps running.
现在打开一个继续运行的进程。
Something simple like a vim editor.
像VIM编辑器这样简单的东西。
And then we can use the other shell to execute `ps aux` to list all running processes.
然后我们可以使用另一个shell来执行'ps aux'，列出所有正在运行的进程。
Now we have to search a bit, but here it is.
现在我们要搜索一下，但在这里。
The first column tells us the user of the running process.
第一列告诉我们正在运行的进程的用户。
And because we as “user” have executed vim, it will run with our privileges.
因为我们作为“用户”已经执行了VIM，所以它将以我们的特权运行。
So no let’s execute one of those setuid binaries and do the same.
所以不，让我们执行其中一个setuid二进制文件并执行相同的操作。
Let’s search the program name.
让我们搜索程序名。
Here it is.
在这里。
BUT do you see the first line?
但是你看到第一行了吗？
It says it’s running as root.
它说它像根一样运行。
What the fuck?
卧槽？
How is that possible?
这怎么可能？
Let’s have a look again at the file permissions.
让我们再看看文件权限。
Ok first of all `r` `dash` `x` means that anybody on the system can read this file and
好的，首先，`r``dash``x`表示系统中的任何人都可以读取此文件，并且
execute it.
执行它。
The next 3 permissions are the same and refer to the permissions for the group.
接下来的3个权限是相同的，并引用组的权限。
A group is just an id, that multiple users could share.
一个组只是一个ID，多个用户可以共享。
So we are in the group that is also called user.
所以我们是一个组，也叫用户。
But theoretically you could group multiple users together.
但是理论上你可以将多个用户组合在一起。
Ok.
好啊。
Now it get’s interesting.
现在它变得有趣了。
The first character indicates if a file is a directory.
第一个字符指示文件是否为目录。
Well it’s not.
但事实并非如此。
So the remaining 3 permissions are for the owner of the file.
所以剩下的3个权限是文件所有者的。
The owner of the file is root.
文件的所有者是根。
And the owner has the permissions to read, write and … S?
并且所有者有读、写和…的权限？
So the s replaced what should be x for executable.
所以s替换了可执行文件的x。
This is called the setuid bit.
这叫做setuid位。
We have already looked at the running process, so you can guess what this does.
我们已经研究了运行过程，所以您可以猜出它的作用。
When this bit is set, and I as a regular user execute it, Linux will actually execute it
当设置了这个位，并且我作为一个普通用户执行它时，Linux将实际执行它。
with the privileges of the owner.
拥有业主的特权。
So in this case it will run as root.
所以在本例中，它将作为根运行。
Why the hell would somebody do this?
为什么会有人这么做？
There are two good examples.
有两个很好的例子。
First, you may know sudo.
首先，你可能知道sudo。
Which is a program that allows you to run something as root if you are a normal user.
这是一个程序，如果你是一个普通的用户，它允许你以根用户的身份运行一些东西。
So how can sudo execute a program as root, even though you typed in the command?
那么，即使您输入了命令，sudo如何以根用户身份执行程序呢？
Well it also has the setuid bit.
它也有setuid位。
Another great example is the ping program.
另一个很好的例子是ping程序。
Ping will also run as root, because it has the setuid bit set.
ping也将作为根运行，因为它设置了setuid位。
Why you ask?
你为什么要问？
Because ping wants to send an ICMP packet which is a fairly low layer.
因为ping想要发送一个相当低层的ICMP包。
And linux generally doesn’t allow normal users to create such raw packets.
Linux通常不允许普通用户创建这样的原始数据包。
But because ping is not evil, somebody created a setuid binary, to allow normal users to
但是，由于ping并不邪恶，有人创建了setuid二进制文件，允许普通用户
send ICMP packets.
发送ICMP数据包。
What if there is an exploit for a program like ping, that would allow you to execute
如果有一个像ping这样的程序的漏洞可以让您执行
arbitrary code as root, right?
任意代码作为根，对吗？
So it’s clear, that setuid can be really dangerous.
所以很明显，赛特乌德是非常危险的。
Well.
好。
And that’s the whole point of the challenges from protostar.
这就是原恒星挑战的全部要点。
If we can exploit one of these programs here, we can escalate privileges and gain root.
如果我们可以利用这些程序中的一个，我们就可以升级特权并获得根目录。
This is basically like jailbreaking on iPhones or rooting on android devices.
这基本上类似于在iPhone上越狱或在Android设备上扎根。
You try to find a vulnerability that allows you to execute arbitrary code in a privileged
您试图找到一个允许您在特权中执行任意代码的漏洞
mode.
模式。
Well, on those real devices, especially iOS this is extremely fucking complicated, and
嗯，在那些真正的设备上，尤其是iOS上，这是非常复杂的，而且
a lot more layers are involved, but now you get a better imagination of the whole thing.
涉及到更多的层，但现在你对整个事情有了更好的想象。
One last thing before we start with the challenges.
在我们开始挑战之前还有最后一件事。
You know that you can debug programs, right?
你知道你可以调试程序，对吗？
For example you can use strace to spy on the system calls.
例如，您可以使用strace监视系统调用。
Or simply use gdb.
或者直接使用gdb。
And gdb allows you to modify memory.
gdb允许您修改内存。
So you could just open this setuid binary in gdb, modify the code and execute whatever
所以您可以在gdb中打开这个setuid二进制文件，修改代码并执行任何
you want as root?
你想要根？
let’s try it.
让我们试试看。
Ok it seems to run.
好的，好像在跑。
So let’s rerun it and look at the process list.
所以让我们重新运行它并查看进程列表。
As you can see it doesn’t run as root anymore.
如你所见，它不再作为根运行了。
The reason is, that gdb could not debug a process that runs as another user.
原因是，gdb无法调试作为另一个用户运行的进程。
So gdb actually forces the binary to NOT run as root so it can actually debug it.
所以gdb实际上强制二进制文件不作为根文件运行，这样它就可以实际调试它了。
So good idea, but unfortunately… or maybe fortunately it’s not that simple.
好主意，但不幸的是……或者幸运的是，这不是那么简单。
I guess we have to rely on good old exploiting techniques.
我想我们必须依靠良好的老剥削技术。
See you in the next video when we start with the first challenge.
当我们开始第一个挑战时，在下一个视频中看到你。